# **Adnan Muhtadi**

Welwyn Garden City, Hertfordshire / +447951258274 adnanmuhtadi@hotmail.com / https://www.linkedin.com/in/adnan-muhtadi

Product Owner/PMO professional with over 8 years of experience supporting enterprise and consumer technology solutions. Champion of supportive team environments with proven success in realising business objectives and implementing internal and consumer-facing IP solutions.

- Project Management / Agile
- Service Delivery Management
- Metadata Schemas
- Microsoft Applications
- Smartsheet

- Power BI and Analytics
- SaaS Web Applications
- Enterprise Cloud Solutions
- JIRA/Atlassian administration
- Office 365

- Zendesk administration
- Service Now administration
- ITIL v4 certification
- Training and Workshops
- Full Stack Web Developer

## **Relevant Work Experience**

# Feb 2021 – Present Vitality – Product Owner/PMO – (Bournemouth)

- Working and defining the Project Management product roadmap while driving the product forward while ensuring the quality of data remains consistent for reporting and audit purposes.
- Liaise between system users and development teams for successful data migration and data validation.
- Identify and address gaps in existing internal processes to increase efficiency in the current working practice.
- Write user stories based on the requirements gathered from all the stakeholders. Capture development requirements for UAT testing of released functionalities.
- Deliver training and adoption for the implemented system and processes, drafting and provisioning release notes and operation manuals while recruiting SMEs across the department.
- Collaborate across Portfolio, Technology, Continuous Service Improvement teams and Build/Development Resources to ensure a joined-up approach to managing the delivery.

### Jul 2020 – Jul 2021 Full Stake Web Developer Course – Code Institute – (Remote/Diploma)

- Whilst reflecting on my career, I identified that my biggest challenge was effectively understanding the role of the developers that I worked closely with. To address this, I enrolled on a course to become a qualified Full Stack Web Developer.
- The course entailed front-end software development and key UX techniques while being competent in CSS, JavaScript & Python. I also became proficient in Bootstrap, Django, Heroku, AWS and understood how Agile development teams worked.
- The course also helped me understand the reason why developers request wireframes & testers request user stories. It also enabled me to understand the technologies better and how they all work together.

### Feb 2019 – Jul 2020 McCann Worldgroup – Product Manager – (London)

- Identified and understood the product gaps in a user's journey and improved the user experience when working on the systems. Analysed product metrics and trends to identify reportable KPIs to track improvements in the product offering.
- Managed a global team consisting of 8 support engineers, 2 business analysts and a product manager undertaking existing projects and new requests to improve the functionalities of the existing overall service.
- Worked closely with the product management team to define the product strategy, vision, design and usability.
- Managed third-party integrations and established strong third-party and vendor relationships while recommending architectural improvements, design and integration solutions.
- Improved global operational processes resulting in a 70% increased efficiency for the system workflow when users are operating on the system.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams across the world to deliver enhancements to the invoice reconciliation system.

#### Jul 2018 - Feb 2019 Giant Group – Project Manager/System Analyst – (London)

- Direct management of 3 junior project managers, leading the team in continuous improvement of controls and implementation processes to reduce non-added value work.
- Owned the development of the product strategy and vision supported by internal and external analysis.
- Managed product work with the screening team, to deliver a new system for screening external candidates.
- Managed multiple projects concurrently while managing all communication with the client.
- Oversaw software developers' progress on applications and applied principles of Agile methodologies to keep projects on track.

#### Sep 2016 – Jul 2018 Hogarth Worldwide – Technical Project Manager – (New York, United States)

- Lead the global implementation of a workflow management tool to standardize the working processes within the company across 20+ global offices.
- Worked collaboratively in an Agile product development team to plan project sprints and achieve project milestones.
- Managed project timelines and communicated with management staff and clients to ensure project progress satisfactorily.

#### Dec 2015 – Sep 2016 Hogarth Worldwide – Service Delivery Engineer – (London)

- Managed 9 Global Service Delivery Analysts conducting ongoing internal team meetings to set priorities and timely resolve outstanding issues and following up if the service is meeting expectations.
- Liaised with 3rd party support providers and participated in Major Incident Handling to ensure that SLAs and OLAs are adhered to regarding the customers and stakeholders.
- Monitored overall performance of services including service management, incident management, problem management and change management as well as the delivery performance within the ITIL structure.

### **Education and Qualifications**

Dec 2021 **ITIL v4 Foundation** July 2021 **Full Stack Web Developer** Nov 2016 **PRINCE2 Foundation** Sep 2009 – Jun 2013 **University of Hertfordshire** 

BSc (Hons) (SW) Information Technology (Web-Based Systems) – Upper Second Class (2:1)

# **Interests and Achievements**

#### 2009 **Computer Science and Engineering Scholarship**

 Due to achieving exceptionally high grades and projects, I received a Science and Engineering Scholarship to study at The University of Hertfordshire

### **Assistant Fund Raiser**

Raised money for The National Coaching Foundation as well as the Alzheimer's Society Campaign

# **Hobbies and Further Competencies**

Bilingual fluency in both English and Arabic Languages Driving Full clean driving licence.

Enjoy experiencing new cultures and countries, which has allowed me to witness and learn from some of the world's most beautiful and individual societies.

### References

2006

Travelling